(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.3",
"generated_at": "2026-07-02T11:15:33.194022",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 16,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
唸るぜ
I'll howl!
血泥ついたって
Even if covered in blood and mud
守りたい
I want to protect you
革命道中
On a revolutionary journey
だって 君に夢中
Because I'm crazy about you
暗闇 染め込む 世界で
In a world soaked in darkness
見つけた
I found you
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love
甘く のたうんだ
Sweetly writhing
眼差し
gaze
変に
Strangely
色気あるから 困った
It's troubling how alluring you are
手を つなぐ 勇気
The courage to hold hands
出したくて
I wanted to muster
身の程
Knowing my place...
わきまえてちゃ 出来ないね
...I wouldn't be able to do it
暗いトンネルの壁
The dark tunnel walls
したたり落ちる秘密
Dripping secrets
死ねやかに...
Elegantly dying...
艶やかに 高鳴る心
Elegantly, my throbbing heart...
ダメダメ 待って待って
No, no, wait, wait!
呪いも病も 抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both the curse and the illness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
I wonder if it's okay to wild out around here.
あぁ 唸るぜ
Ah, it's roaring!
ちから ついたって 守りたい
Even if I gain power, I want to protect you.
革命道中 だって君に夢中
On the road of revolution, because I'm crazy about you.
暗闇 染み込む 世界で見つけた
Found in a world where darkness seeps in...
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
なりふり構わず 側にいたい
Regardless of appearances, I want to be by your side.
不器用な君にも期待しちゃうよ
I end up expecting things from clumsy you, too.
しがみつけば 消えそうな灯に
Clinging to the light that seems about to go out,
恋の爪立てて 近づいて
I dig in love's claws and get closer.
身を任せるからさ 全て失ってもいい
I'll surrender myself, so I don't mind losing everything.
艶やかに 高鳴る心
Elegantly, my throbbing heart...
ダメダメ 待って待って
No, no, wait, wait!
呪いも病も 君となら
Curses and illness, if it's with you...
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいかな
I wonder if it's okay to wild out around here.
あぁ 泣けるぜ
Ah, it makes me cry!
絶句しちゃうまで 離れない
Until I'm left speechless, I won't let go.
革命道中 だって君に夢中
On the road of revolution, because I'm crazy about you.
旅の狭間で 見つけた
Found in the midst of the journey...
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
突き進むなら二人で
If we are to push forward, let it be the two of us.
革命道中 だって夢に熱中
On the road of revolution, because I'm obsessed with my dream.
ダメダメ 待って待って
No, no, wait, wait!
呪いも病も 抱きしめたい
I want to embrace both the curse and the illness.
ここらで暴れちゃってもいいよね
Is it okay if I wild out around here?
怖くたって 唸るぜ
Even if I'm scared, it roars!
ちから ついたって 守りたい
Even if I gain power, I want to protect you.
革命道中 だって君に夢中
On the road of revolution, because I'm crazy about you.
暗闇 染み込む 世界で見つけた
Found in a world where darkness seeps in...
センチメンタルな恋
A sentimental love.
いくぞー！
Here we go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
そっと吐き出すため息を吸い込んだ
I quietly inhaled the sigh I breathed out.
後悔は苦い味残して
Regret left behind a bitter taste.
いつもなんで？ 肝心なこと言えないまま
Always, why? Unable to say what's essential,
次の朝日が顔出してる
the next morning sun is showing its face.
嫌になった運命をナイフで切り刻んで
I carved up the fate I grew sick of with a knife.
もう一度やり直したら
If I redo it once more,
キミに出会えないかも
maybe I won't meet you.
僕の声が響いた瞬間に始まる
At the moment my voice echoed, it begins.
命のリミット 心臓がカウントしてる
The limit of life, my heart is counting.
叶えても 叶えても終わらない願い
Even if I fulfill it, even if I fulfill it, the wish won't end.
汗をかいて走った世界の秒針は
The second hand of the world I ran while sweating through
いつか止まった僕を置いていく
will someday stop and leave me behind.
あと何回キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ僕を Catch the Moment
I am testing myself, Catch the Moment.
一個幸せを数えるたびに
Every time I count one happiness,
変わっていく未来に怯えてしまうけど
I fear the future that keeps changing, but
愛情の種を大切に育てよう
let's cherish and nurture the seeds of affection.
分厚い雲もやがて突き破るかな
Maybe it will pierce through the thick clouds someday.
キミの声が響いた僕の全身を通って
Your voice echoed through my whole body,
心臓のドアをノックしてる
knocking on the door of my heart.
「臆病」でも開けちゃうんだよ信じたいから
Even if I am a "coward", I'll open it because I want to believe.
何にもないと思ったはずの足元に
Under my feet where I thought there was nothing at all,
何にもないと思った
I thought there was nothing...
はずの足元に
under my feet.
深く...
Deeply...
確かな根を生やす
growing deep, solid roots.
嵐の夜が来たとしても
Even if a stormy night should come,
揺らいだりはしない
I won't waver.
何度も 追いついたり 追い越し たり
Time and again, catching up and overtaking,
キミがふいに分かんなくなって
suddenly I can't understand you.
息をしたタイミングが
Just because our breathing...
合うだけで嬉しくなったりして
...matches, I become so happy.
集めた一秒を
The single seconds I've gathered...
永遠にして
...can I make them eternal...
行けるかな
...as we go forward?
僕の声が響いた
The moment my voice resounds,
瞬間に始まる
it all begins:
命のリミット
the limit of my life.
心臓がカウントしてる
My heart is counting down.
叶えても 叶えても
Even if it is granted, even if it comes true,
終わらない願い
this wish has no end.
汗をかいて走った 世界の秒針が
In dripping sweat, the seconds hand of this world...
いつか止まった 僕を置いていく
...will one day leave me behind when I stop.
あと何回 キミと笑えるの？
How many more times can I laugh with you?
試してるんだ 僕を
This world is testing me.
Catch the moment
逃さないよ 僕は"
I won't let it go!
この瞬間を掴め
I'll seize this moment!
Catch the moment
こんばんどどどー！
Good evening, dododo!
お誕生日を2回迎えることになった...
I ended up celebrating my birthday twice...
角巻わためです！
I'm Tsunomaki Watame!
本当は6月6日が誕生日なんですけど
Actually, my birthday is June 6th, but...
グルグルが多くて中断、そして延期になり...
due to lots of buffering, it was interrupted and postponed...
今日！角巻わため生誕祭2026 アニソンナイトフィーバー2！
Today! Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2026: Anisong Night Fever 2!
改めて開催させていただくことになりました！
We are holding it once again!
迅速に動いてくださった運営さんたち！
The staff who moved so quickly!
そしてライブを見に来てくれている皆さん！
And everyone who came to watch the live show!
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
1曲目「革命デュアリズム」、2曲目「Catch the Moment」と見ていただいて
After watching the first song, "Kakumei Dualism", and the second song, "Catch the Moment"...
分かった方もいるかもしれないんですが
some of you might have noticed,
前回のライブで放送した部分は
the parts that were broadcasted in the previous live show...
万が一のために録画を回してくださっていたので
...were recorded in case of an emergency.
そちらの6月6日のバキバキ生誕当日のパフォーマンスを見ていただいて
So, you watched the performance from June 6th, the actual birthday itself.
それ以外のソロとMCは改めて
But the other solos and MC parts...
これ以上ライブが延期にならないように
...to prevent the live show from being postponed any further,
今回は事前に収録をさせていただきました！
we recorded them in advance this time!
なので未来のリアルタイムの皆のコメントを
So, while predicting the real-time comments...
予知しながらMCしたいなと思いますので
...from the future during this MC,
いっぱいコメントしてください！
please write lots of comments!
うん、うん、わかったよ、はい、はい、うん。
Yeah, yeah, I see. Okay, okay, yeah.
うん、あ、ありがとうね。
Yeah, oh, thank you.
「おめでとう」もありがとう！見える、見えるぞ！
Thank you for the "Happy Birthday" too! I can see them, I can see them!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
説明はここまで！
That's it for the explanation!
ここからはいつものライブ！
From here on, it's the usual live show!
今日は生誕ライブなので、たくさんこのライブに向けて
Since today is my birthday live, for this live show,
準備や練習を、本当にたくさんしてきました！
I really did a lot of preparation and practice!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんで、そしていっぱいお祝いしてもらえると嬉しいです！
I hope you enjoy it to the end, and I'd be happy if you celebrate a lot with me!
本日のハッシュタグは、こちら！
Today's hashtag is this!
6月6日と変わらず「角巻わため生誕祭2026」になりますので
It remains the same as June 6th, "Tsunomaki Watame Birthday Celebration 2026"...
たくさんスクショとか感想とかポストしてください！
so please post lots of screenshots and thoughts!
目指せ、またトレンド1位！
Let's aim for #1 trending again!
後でじっとり、ねっとり、わためも見に行きたいと思ってますので、よろしくお願いします！
I will also be creeping around and checking them closely later, so please do so!
では、ここまで『革命デュアリズム』
Well, up to this point, "Kakumei Dualism"...
『Catch the Moment』と歌わせていただいたんですが
and "Catch the Moment" were sung.
アニメや原曲MVに関連している演出を取り入れたりしているので
Since we incorporated staging related to the anime and the original MV...
皆、分かったかな？
I wonder if everyone noticed?
ターボわためとか、分かったかな？
Like "Turbo Watame", did you get it?
ぜひ細かいところまで見てもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you look closely at the details!
ここからはゲストパートもあります！
From here on, we also have guest parts!
皆の好きなアニソンも出てくるかも？
Your favorite anisongs might show up too!
ということで、ゲストパート盛り上がっていきましょう！
With that said, let's fire up the guest parts!
アンバランスなKissをして
[Song: Exchange an Unbalanced Kiss]
割れた鏡の中
In the cracked mirror
映る君の姿
Your reflection is shown
泣いている
Crying
細い月をなぞる指
Fingers tracing the thin moon
誰を呼んでいるの
Who are you calling for?
消えた恋の背中
The back of a vanished love
何度でも 何度でも
Again and again, again and again
君の窓を叩くから
I'll knock on your window
夜の加速度に
By the acceleration of the night
背中押されて
Being pushed from behind
糸が切れる様に
Like a thread snapping
ただ、君を 君を強く
I was just holding you, holding you strongly...
抱いてた
...holding you close
アンバランスなKissを交わして
Exchange an unbalanced kiss
愛に近づけよ
And get closer to love
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Even your tears, even your sad lies
僕の心に
In my heart...
眠れ
...sleep
昨日へのMerry-go-round
Merry-go-round to yesterday
君を運んでゆく
Carrying you away
止めたくて 止めたくて
I want to stop it, I want to stop it
僕は鍵を探してる
I'm searching for the key
崩れ落ちそうな空を支えて
Supporting the sky that's about to collapse
ひとり立ち尽くす
I stand all alone
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be...
いたいよ
...by your side
アンバランスなKissで書かれた
Written with an unbalanced kiss
ふたりのシナリオ
The script of the two of us
愛と呼ぶほど 強くなくても
Even if it's not strong enough to be called love
君のすべてが 痛い
Everything about you is painful
ただ、君の 君の側に
I just want to be...
いたいよ
...by your side
アンバランスなKissを交わして
Exchange an unbalanced kiss
愛に近づけよ
And get closer to love
君の涙も 哀しい嘘も
Even your tears, even your sad lies
僕の心に
In my heart...
眠れ
...sleep
君の心が僕を呼ぶまで
Until your heart calls out to me
抱きしめあえる日まで
Until the day we can hold each other again
GHOST SWEEPER
[Song: GHOST SWEEPER]
長い髪なびかせて
Letting your long hair flutter
悩ましげなボディ
A teasing body
この都会をハイヒールで
Through this city in high heels
飛び回れば Big money coming, yeah!
If you fly around, big money coming, yeah!
摩天楼の足下
At the foot of the skyscraper
時代錯誤の罠
A trap of anachronism
血迷った 危ない奴らなら
If you're a dangerous guy who has gone astray
極楽へいかせちゃうわ
I'll send you to paradise
大胆な
Daring...
大胆な私の業（わざ）の中どれでも
From any of my bold techniques,
スキなのをあげる
I'll give you what you like.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
行き場のない あなた Ghost だから…
Because you're a Ghost with nowhere to go...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
私が今 見つけ出して…
I'll find you out right now...
Ghost Sweeper
吸印（きゅういん）もいいけれど神道棍（しんとうこん）はどう？
Sucking marks are fine too, but how about the 'Shintsu-kon' (Spiritual Staff)?
わがままは 許さないわ
I won't allow selfishness.
逃がせないの Big money coming, yeah!
I can't let you escape. Big money coming, yeah!
コンシャスなドレスから ゴージャスなライフも
From a conscious dress, to a gorgeous life,
いつだって 後からついてくる
it always follows from behind,
それが私のスタイル
that's my style.
クールだと誰かがいうけれど 必ず
Though someone says it's cool, I will surely...
幸せをあげる
...bring you happiness.
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
行き場のない
...with nowhere to go...
あなた Ghost だから…
...because you're a Ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
私が今
...I'll find you out...
見つけ出して…
...right now...
Ghost Sweeper
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
行き場のない
...with nowhere to go...
あなた Ghost だから…
...because you're a Ghost...
Bye Bye Sadness, And Find out
私が今
...I'll find you out...
見つけ出して…
...right now...
Ghost Sweeper
魂の色は
What color...
何色ですか
...is the soul?
「もういっそ 折れたままで」
"If you're going to break, just stay broken"
捨てるほど 逃げ出すほど
To throw it all away, to run away,
強くないよ ほら
I'm not strong enough. Look,
もう一度 鼓動 高鳴る
my heartbeat is quickening once again.
何が正しいかなんて
Though I don't know...
わからないけど
...what is right...
形のないものばかりが
...things without shape...
大切になって行く
...are becoming precious to me.
飾らない言葉だけが
Only words without pretense...
強く結ばれてる
...are tightly bound.
また躓いて 転がって
I stumble again, I tumble...
それでも砕けない
...even then, I don't break.
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって
Just getting hurt, just putting on a brave face...
それでも見つけたいよ
...even then, I want to find it...
魂のカタチ
...the shape of the soul...
確かめてるよ
...I'm confirming it.
深い地の底で一人
Alone at the bottom of the deep earth...
扉と鍵を探す
...searching for the door and the key.
おとぎ話は ほら
Fairytales are, look,
泡の様に全部消えて
gone like bubbles, all of them...
葛藤 残像だけ
...only conflicts and afterimages...
次の頁へ
...to the next page.
伸びてく枝葉が分かれて
The branches that extend divide...
それぞれの道を行く
...and go on their separate ways.
...道を行く
...our own ways.
寂しい思い出だけが
Only lonely memories
強く根を張ってる
are deeply rooted.
まだ貫いて失って それでも挫けない保存
Though I still press on and lose, I still won't give up.
心はどこに
Where is my heart?
器はどこに
Where is its vessel?
ただ残されて抜け落ちて それでも伝えたいよ
Just left behind and empty, yet I still want to tell you
魂の日々を
about the soul's days,
魂の意志を
about the soul's will,
ずっと
forever...
魂の色は
What is the color
何色ですか
of my soul?
赤色ですか
Is it red?
青色ですか
Is it blue?
魂の色は
What is the color
何色ですか
of my soul?
透明な過去に 不透明な明日に
In a transparent past, in an opaque tomorrow,
生きるあなたは 何色ですか
you who live, what color are you?
また躓いて 転がってk
I tripped and tumbled again,
それでも 砕けない
but I'm still unbreakable!
魂の色は 何色ですか
What color is the soul?
ただ傷ついて 強がって それでも見つけたいよ
Just getting hurt and acting tough, yet I still want to find it—
魂のカタチ 確かめてるよk
confirming the shape of my soul.
ずっと
Forever...
いぇーい！ 3曲連続でお届けしましたが、
Yay! We delivered three songs in a row,
みんな、楽しんでますかー？
is everyone having fun?
快適に見れてますかー？
Are you able to watch comfortably?
え、幽☆遊☆白書の『アンバランスなKissをして』は、月をね、写してもらったり、
Um, for Yu Yu Hakusho's "Unbalance na Kiss o Shite", we had the moon shown,
戦闘シーンをイメージして炎に囲まれていたり、
being surrounded by flames inspired by the battle scenes,
ダンスの振りにもね、キャラクターの技が入っていたりしておりまして、
and characters' special moves were incorporated into the dance choreography.
『GS美神』の『GHOST SWEEPER』にも、お札をね、持っている振りがあったり、
For GS Mikami's "GHOST SWEEPER", there was a choreo of holding paper charms,
あとは幽霊が飛んでいる、そんな演出があったりしました。気づいたかな？
and there was also an effect with flying ghosts! Did you notice?
そして、『ソードアート・オンライン』の『ANIMA』は、いつか歌いたいと思っていた曲で、
Also, Sword Art Online's "ANIMA" was a song I've wanted to sing someday,
満を持しての披露だったんですが、いかがだったんでしょうか？
so this was a long-awaited performance. How did you like it?
いや、カッコよかったなー！すごいなー、わためバキバキだなー！
Man, that was so cool! Amazing, Watame was totally rocking it!
ふふ、でも！まだこれで終わりではありません！
Hehe, but! This is not the end yet!
ここからは、鏡、ゲートを使ったギミックや、やってみたかった演出なども入ってくるので、
From here on, gimmicks using mirrors and gates, and stage effects I've always wanted to try will be introduced,
さらに盛り上がる、爆上げセトリをいっぱいやっていきたいと思います！
so we will perform lots of hyped-up setlists to fire things up even more!
それでは、行ってきまーす！
Well then, here I go!
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
An unbeatable smile, stirring up the media,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know that secret, so mysterious.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリアy
Even her clumsy traits are within her area.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, so perfect and a liar,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius-like idol!
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything.
それは内緒
That's a secret.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
No matter what you ask, dodging evasively.
そう淡々と
So nonchalantly,
だけど燦々と
yet so brilliantly.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
The secrets that seem visible yet invisible taste like honey.
あれもない ない ない
There's none of that, that, that.
これもない ない ない
There's none of this, this, this.
好きなタイプは？
What is your type?
相手は？
Who is your partner?
さあ答えて
Come on, answer us!
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
"I don't even know what it's like to love someone."
そんな言葉に...
Once again, there's somebody who's fallen for those words...
また一人堕ちる
falling for them.
また好きにさせる
Making them fall in love with you again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone is captivated by you.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
Because you are perfect, the most ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない
Unrivaled, you will never appear again.
一番星の生まれ変わり
You are indeed the brightest star reborn.
Ah その笑顔で愛してるで野
Ah, with that smiling face, saying "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく野
everyone is lured and captivated by you.
その瞳がその言葉が
Those eyes, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if untrue, they represent your perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Right, right, we all know she's very special.
我々はハナからおまけです
We were just extras right from the very start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We are just B-list actors to make the star shine.
全てがあの子の御陰なわけない
No way everything is thanks to her grace.
洒落臭い
How ridiculous.
妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない野
How could we not feel jealous and envious?
これはネタじゃない
This isn't just a joke,
からこそ許せない
which is exactly why I can't forgive you.
完璧じゃない
I can't forgive you for being imperfect.
君じゃ許せない
I won't accept you.
自分を許せない
I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't allow anyone else except you, the strongest.
誰もが信じ崇めてる野
Everyone believes in and worships you.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル野
Indeed, you are the strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない野
There are no weaknesses to be found in you.
一番星を宿している野
The brightest star is residing within you.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ野
You must never, ever show your weak side.
知りたくないところは見せずに野
Keep hidden the parts they don't want to see.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ野
You must be the one and only, no, no!
それこそ本物のアイ野
That's what true love really is.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア野
Boiling up the media with your specialty smile.
隠しきるこの秘密だけは野
Keeping this secret hidden deep inside.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア野s
Building a career on the lie of "I love you."
これこそ私なりの愛だ野s
This is my own way of showing love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア野s
Even flowing sweat is beautiful aqua.
ルビーを隠したこの瞼野s
A ruby hidden under these eyelids.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア野s
I sing and dance, look at me, I'm Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ野s
Yes, lying is surely the greatest kind of love.
誰かに愛されたことも野s
I recall no one that loved me before,
誰かのこと愛したこともない野s
and I've not been in love with anyone before.
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること野s
I hope that one day, my lies will become the truth.
信じてる野s
I believe it.
ロールケーキ わためとキッスを
Roll cake, a kiss with Watame
ミルフィーユワッフルボンボン
Mille-feuille, waffle, bonbon
ムースわためパイ
Mousse, Watame, pie
シュークリーム バナナゼリー
Cream puff, banana jelly
ババロアわため
Bavarois, Watame
ホットケーキ バウムクーヘン
Pancake, baumkuchen
わためわため
Watame, Watame
バターわためクレープ
Butter, Watame, crepe
わためわため
Watame, Watame
わためとごはん
Watame and meals!
わためとおやつ
Watame and snacks!
わためと肉まん
Watame and meat buns!
わためと北京ダック
Watame and Peking duck!
みつまめわため
Mitsumame, Watame!
わためシロップ
Watame syrup!
金時わため
Kintoki, Watame!
大盛りわためどーぞ
A large serving of Watame, here you go!
こんがり
Toasted golden brown...
思い出色
The color of memories...
ハチミツ
Honey...
みたいにとろける
Melting just like...
あ、い、う、え、お菓子した
A, I, U, E, I ate some candy
か、き、く、け、こんなにも
Ka, Ki, Ku, Ke, so very much
さ、し、す、せ、ソフトクリーム
Sa, Shi, Su, Se, soft serve ice cream
五臓六腑でいこう
Let's go with everything we've got!
た、ち、つ、て、トルテ切った
Ta, Chi, Tsu, Te, I cut the torte
な、に、ぬ、ね、のり塩
Na, Ni, Nu, Ne, norishio flavor
は、ひ、ふ、へ、ホットパイと
Ha, Hi, Fu, He, hot pie and
三人でぬくぬく
The three of us getting nice and warm
ま、み、む、め、モンブラン
Ma, Mi, Mu, Me, Mont Blanc
や、い、ゆ、え、ヨーグルト
Ya, I, Yu, E, yogurt
ら、り、る、れ、ロールケーキ
Ra, Ri, Ru, Re, roll cake
わためとキッスを
A kiss with Watame!
わための甘味と
Watame's sweetness, and
わための苦味
Watame's bitterness, and
わための酸味で
Watame's sourness...
すきすきラブ・コンボ
I love it, love combo!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is also a crazy, bustling uproar!
うー！ がおー！
Woo! Gao!
高らかに笑い笑えば フレンズ
Laughing out loud makes us friends!
フレンズ
Friends!
喧嘩して すっちゃかめっちゃかしても
Even if we fight and get all topsy-turvy,
仲良し
We are still close friends!
けものは居ても
There are beasts,
のけものは居ない
But no outcasts!
本当の愛は ここに ある
True love is right here!
ほら 君も
Look, you too,
手を つないで 大冒険
Hand in hand, let's go on a big adventure!
ワン・ツー・スリー
One, two, three!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is also a crazy, bustling uproar!
姿かたちも 十人十色 だから 惹かれ合うの
Different in shape and size, to each their own, that's why we are drawn to each other!
夕暮れ空に
In the twilight sky,
指をそっと 重ねたら
If we gently overlap our fingers...
はじめまして
Nice to meet you!
君を もっと 知りたいな
I want to know more about you!
うー！ がおー！
Woo! Gao!
振り向けば あちらこちらで トラブル
If we look back, there's trouble here and there!
トラブル
Trouble!
なんてこった てんでんバラバラちんぷんかんぷん
Oh my god, scattered and chaotic, it makes no sense!
まとまらない
We just can't keep it together!
けものですもの 大目に見てね
We are beasts after all, so please go easy on us!
みんな自由に 生きている
Everyone lives as freely as they want!
そう 君も
That's right, you too,
飾らなくて 大丈夫
You don't have to put on a show, it's alright!
はい どうぞ
Here you go!
Nice to meet you ようこそジャパリパーク！
Nice to meet you, welcome to Japari Park!
今日からどうぞよろしくね
Let's get along well starting today!
いつもいつでも優しい笑顔
Always and forever, with a gentle smile...
君を待っていたの
I've been waiting for you!
開かれた扉 夢をいっぱい語ったら
If we open the door and talk endlessly about our dreams,
どこまででも
No matter how far,
続いていく グレートジャーニー
The great journey continues!
うー！ がおー！
Woo! Gao!
東へ吠えろ
Howl to the east!
西へ吠えろ
Howl to the west!
世界中
Throughout the whole world,
に響け サファリメロディ
let the safari melody ring out!
Welcome to ようこそジャパリパーク！
Welcome to, welcome to Japari Park!
今日もドッタンバッタン大騒ぎ
Today is also a crazy, bustling uproar!
姿かたちも 十人十色 だから 惹かれ合うの
Different in shape and size, to each their own, that's why we are drawn to each other!
指をそっと 重ねたら
In the twilight sky, if we gently overlap our fingers...
はじめまして 君を もっと 知りたいな
Nice to meet you! I want to know more about you!
君を もっと 知りたいな
I want to know more about you...
うー！ がおー！
Woo! Gao!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク！
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ ララララ
La la la la, la la la la
集まれ友達 夜空に響け
Gather round, friends! Ring out into the night sky!
ララララ
La la la la
Oh, Welcome to the ジャパリパーク!
Oh, Welcome to the Japari Park!
ララララ
La la la la
ララララララ
La la la la la la
素敵な旅立ち
A wonderful departure
ようこそジャパリパーク!
Welcome to Japari Park!
Fire!
Oh, oh, oh...
Fire! Fire! Fire!
Night of fire!
Fire!
Welcome to the broken low
Welcome to the famous disco live
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, get me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, rock it, rock it, knock to my door, oh
Speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire,
you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my rocky show
Welcome to the fire of the night
Come on baby, let it go
Come on baby, let me stick you tight
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, rock it, rock it, knock to my door, oh
Speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the
Night of fire,
you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better, better stay
You've better, better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire,
come over, over me
Come over, over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
You've better, better stay
the prayer to play
Come over, over me
You've never been here
Night of fire,
you've better, better begin
Night of fire
Come over, over the top
you'll have a night of fire
Welcome to my broken world
Welcome to the famous disco night
Come on lady, come and go
Come on lady, give me once and right
Not a danger, not a blacky stranger
Rock it, rock it, knock to my door I'll open
Speak my name now, speak it if you know how
Fly to me, get ready for the...
Night of fire, you better, better stay
You better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come on, come over me
Come over the top, you've never been here
Night of fire, you better, better stay
You better begin the prayer to play
Night of fire, come on, come over me
Come over the top, you'll have a night of fire
You'll have a night of fire
ということで、ここまでたくさんの！
With that, we've had so many...
本当たくさんのゲストさんたちと、歌って踊ってきましたが、いかがだったでしょうか？
really, so many guests join us to sing and dance, how did you like it?
楽しんでますかー？
Are you having fun?
なかなかね、こんなにホロメンが集まることってないので、もう本当、生誕祭、お祭りって感じで嬉しいです！
Since it's rare for so many Holomembers to gather like this, I'm really happy, it feels like a real festival for my birthday!
ゲストさんたちにも、大きな拍手をー！
Let's give a big round of applause to our guests as well!
ありがとう、みんなー！ゲストのみんな、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone! Thank you to all the guests!
いや、このね、鏡のモニターから登場するという演出をやってみたいなと思って
I really wanted to try having guests appear from these mirror monitors,
アイドルとスウィーツパレードで実現していただきました！
and they made it happen during "Idol" and "Sweets Parade"!
あの、わためいと、スバル先輩、エルフレ先輩たちが、ペンライトをね、振ってくれてたのも可愛かったし
Also, it was cute how the Watamates, Subaru-senpai, and Elfriends were waving penlights for us,
やっぱりホロメンって可愛いよなー！
and indeed, Holomembers are so cute!
あと、「ようこそジャパリパークへ」ではサバンナで肉食動物たちに囲まれて、虎のような人間がいたような気もしますが
Also, in "Welcome to Japari Park", we were surrounded by carnivores in the savanna, and I felt like there was a tiger-like human there...
みんながね、仲良くなっていく様子を表現させていただきました！
...but we wanted to express how everyone became good friends!
まあ、ちょっとね、最後みんなの表情怪しかったけどね
Well, everyone's expressions at the end were a bit suspicious, though!
そして、Night of Fire！これはもう、英語の上手なEN・IDメンバーのみんなと一緒に歌いたいと思って<
And "Night of Fire"! I wanted to sing this with the EN and ID members who are fluent in English,
横に立って歌っても浮かないように、英語頑張んだんだけど、大丈夫だったかな？海外ニキ！
so I worked hard on my English so I wouldn't stand out standing next to them. Was it okay, overseas bros?!
うんうん、「英語上手」「英語上手」ってコメントが来てると思う！ありがとうございます！
Yeah, yeah, I'm sure comments like "Your English is good" are coming in! Thank you so much!
でも、みんなもっと気になるところがね、あったかなと思うんですが
But I think there might be something else everyone is curious about...
あ、車ね！攻めてたね！
Oh, the car! That was quite bold, wasn't it?
あとは、パラパラ踊るギリ割るロボね！
And also the Guriwaru Robot dancing parapara!
やりたい放題させていただいて、とっても楽しかったです！
I got to do whatever I wanted, and it was so much fun!
でも！まだ終わりじゃない！
But! It's not over yet!
ちょっと着替えてくるので、待っててください！
I'm going to go change, so please wait a moment!
よいしょ、よいしょ。よいしょ、よいしょ。着替えて、着替えて、よいしょ、よいしょ。ふぅ、はぁ
Yoisho, yoisho... changing, changing... phew, haa...
あ、もう着替え終わった！
Ah, I'm already done changing!
えー、さて、次の曲なんですが
Now then, as for the next song...
なんと、なんかみんなもう知ってそうだけど、次の曲は新曲！
Incredibly, though it seems everyone already knows, the next song is a brand new song!
「灰色の証明」をやります！
I will be performing "Grey Proof"!
わためチャンネルにてMV公開中なので、MVもぜひ見てください！
The MV is currently out on the Watame Channel, so please check it out too!
そして、楽曲リリースもしているので、いいなと思ったら、ぜひ買ってください！よろしくお願いします！
And since the digital single is also released, if you like it, please buy it! Thank you!
では、新曲「灰色の証明」、魂を込めて歌います。聴いてください
Now, my new song "Grey Proof". I will sing it with all my soul. Please listen to it.
静寂に包まれた
Wrapped in silence...
ゼロ地点の感情を
the emotion at ground zero...
期待を背負っているのは
Because the one carrying expectations...
私ではないから
is not me.
主人公はいつだって
The protagonist is always...
輝いている誰かで
someone who shines,
見上げるだけじゃ何も変わらない
and just looking up won't change anything.
今この時だけの
With a temporary advantage...
瞬間的な優位性で 駆け抜けて
that is only for this very moment, run through!
灰色の空 裂いて
Tear open the grey sky,
私の全てを
with all of me...
運命のシナリオに
slam against the scenario of fate...
叩きつけて打ち砕け
and shatter it!
自信は微塵もない
I don't have a shred of confidence,
あるのは渇望だけ
all I have is craving.
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
I'll just prove my own existence,
此処にいたことを刻むように
as if engraving the fact that I was "here".
綺麗な勝ち方は 望むべくもない
There's no hope for a beautiful way to win
華やかさも必要ない それが私だから
No need for flamboyance, because that is who I am
歴史はいつだって 勝者が作るモノ
History is always made by the winners
だけど記憶はその限りじゃない
But memory is not limited to that
今 この時だけは
Just for this moment
決断的な刹那性に 飛び込んでいけ
Jump into the decisive moment
灰色の世界描く
Drawing the grey world
私の思いが
My thoughts
美しき痛みをも 乗り越えて書き換えてく
Overcome even the beautiful pain and rewrite it
後悔は1ミリもない
There's not a single millimeter of regret
あるのは灼熱だけ
All that's there is burning heat
ただ自分の生命を蹴り上げるように
Just to kick up my own life
始まりは些細も 最早どうだっていい
A small beginning doesn't even matter anymore
突き動かされ指先を伸ばす
Moved, I stretch out my fingertips
現実は残酷だと気付いていないわけじゃない
I'm not unaware that reality is cruel
諦めるその時は 今ではなかったらしい
It seems the time to give up wasn't now
灰色の空 赤く染めて もう一度点火して
Dyeing the grey sky red, igniting once again
ただ自分の生命を証明しよう
Just to prove my own life
そこにいたことを刻むように
As if to carve that I was there
はい！ということで、新曲『灰色の証明』
Yes! So, my new song "Haiiro no Shoumei"
やっと披露できたー！
I finally got to perform it!
やっと証明できたー！
I finally proved it!
聞いてくれてありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much for listening!
この楽曲は、岸田教団&THE明星ロケッツの皆さんに
This song was produced by
制作していただきまして、スポーツだったり
Kishida Kyoudan & THE Akeboshi Rockets.
みんなが頑張りたい時に力になれるような
I wanted to make an encouraging song
応援ソングを作りたいと思い、いろいろ語ったら
that can give strength to everyone. After discussing ideas,
かなり熱くてかっこいい楽曲に仕上がりました！
it turned out to be an incredibly hot and cool song!
うまく行かないことがあっても、また立ち上がって
Even when things don't go well, standing back up
前に進む、わためにとっても背中を押してくれる
and moving forward... it's a song that pushes my back too.
そんな特別な楽曲に今回のライブでなりました！
Through this live show, it has become special for me!
みんなにとってもそうだったら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if it's the same for everyone!
こちらの新曲MVいっぱい見て
Please watch the MV for this new song a lot,
楽曲もぜひ購入して
purchase the track,
わための音楽を応援していただけたらとっても嬉しいです！
and support Watame's music!
目指せ、武道館ライブ！
Let's aim for a Budokan Live!
と！あ、ここでまだ告知していないものが1つありまして
Also! Ah, there is one more announcement that I hasn't made yet.
ライブじゃないんですけど、なんと…
It's not about a live concert, but...
ダダーン！『角巻わためのHave a nice day』が書籍刊行決定！
Ta-da! "Tsunomaki Watame's Have a nice day" book publication decided!
ということで、ハバナが本になります！
So, "HabaNice" is going to be a book!
出版社は、『かいけつゾロリ』や
The publisher is Poplar Publishing, famous for
『おしりたんてい』などで有名なポプラ社様より
"Kaiketsu Zorori" and "Butt Detective"!
オリジナルグッズ付きで12月に刊行予定です！
It's scheduled to be published in December with original merch!
まだ少し先にはなりますが、楽しみに待ってもらえると嬉しいです！
It's still a bit away, but please look forward to it!
そして、ドダーン！今年も角巻わため誕生日記念グッズが受注受付中です！
And, ta-da! Tsunomaki Watame birthday merch is now available for pre-order!
ラインナップを改めて紹介させてくださーい！
Let me introduce the lineup once again!
ド、ド、ド、ド、ドン！チャチャーン！
Ta-da!
ふーみママ描き下ろしの『わためのあったかブランケット』！
"Watame's Warm Blanket" newly illustrated by Fumi-mama!
なんと、セクシーです！
It's so sexy!
そして、裏面にはわためいとがいます！
And there's a Watamate on the back!
丸めるとね、わためいとの形になりますので、2wayでも使えます！
If you roll it up, it takes the shape of a Watamate!
ぜひ温もりを感じてください！
Please feel the warmth!
そして、ド、ド、ド、ド、ダン！
And next, ta-da!
『わため&わためいと 温感マグカップ』！
"Watame & Watamate Thermosensitive Mug"!
こちらはモタ先生に描き下ろしていただきまして保存する
This one was illustrated by Mota-sensei.
最初は夜の風景なんですけど、温かいものを入れていただくと
It starts as a night scene, but if you pour a hot drink,
その熱を感知して、朝の景色に柄が変わるような仕様になっております！
the pattern changes to a morning scene!
わための配信を意識してデザインしてもらったので
Designed with Watame's streams in mind,
配信を見ながらぜひ温かい飲み物を飲んでくださいね！
enjoy a hot drink while watching my streams!
そして、まだあります！
And, there's more!
ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ド、ダン！
(Drumroll...)
『わためいとクッション』！クッションとして使うも良し、飾るも良し…
"Watamate Cushion"! Good as a cushion, good as a decoration...
...に置いてみてください！
...please try placing it!
はい！
Okay!
最後に！
And finally!
ドゥルルルルルルルルルル、ダン！
Ta-da!
じゃーん！わためなりきりアイマスク！
Ta-da! The Watame Cosplay Eye Mask!
眠っている顔と...
With a sleeping face and...
わためと言えばこれ！な表情にしていただきました！
this expression that instantly screams Watame!
果たして需要はあるのか？
Will there actually be demand for this?
気になる方はぜひ、なりきりアイマスク手に入れてください！
If you're curious, please do grab one!
こちらのグッズをフルセットで購入していただいた方には...
And for those who purchase the full set of these goods...
ドゥルルルルルルルルルル、ダン！
Ta-da!
わための直筆サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカードと...
A postcard with Watame's handwritten autograph and message...
つのまきわためのショートボイスセット15種類が特典としてついてきます！
and a set of 15 short voice clips as a bonus!
今年も無制限で...
This year, as well, there's no limit...
直筆を書かせていただく予定なので、ぜひこの機会にゲットしてみてください！
on how many I'll autograph, so please take this chance!
ということで、新曲MV公開中！
With that said, the new song's MV is now public!
楽曲リリース中！
The song is out now!
誕生日グッズ発売中！
Birthday merchandise is on sale!
12月カバー小説刊行決定！
And a Cover novel publication is set for December!
よろしくお願いいたします！
We hope you look forward to them!
この後は、22時15分からメン限アンコールライブもありますので
After this, starting at 10:15 PM, we have a members-only encore live!
よかったら、メンゲ...あ、間違えた
So please join our memb... ah, I messed up...
メンバーに入っていただいて、引き続き楽しみましょう！
join our membership and let's keep having fun!
今年はなんと2DAYS！
This year is actually 2 days long!
お誕生日たくさんお祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Thank you so much for celebrating my birthday!
めちゃくちゃ嬉しかったです！
I was super, super happy!
それではメン限アンコールライブで会いましょう！
Well then, let's meet at the members-only encore live!
またねー！
See you later!
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams
これからも夢に向かって一緒に歩いて行こうね！
Let's keep walking together toward our dreams!!